

#### **SUMMARY**

Hi, I'm Mo.

I am a UX product designer, developer, and a problem solver, striving to create outstanding user experiences in both digital and physical products.

Alongside my work experience as an architect, I have a master's degree in MediaArchitecture which, in association with the Human-Computer Interaction department, focused on user-interface (UI), user-centered design, and user-research methods.

# **Mohamad G Khalil**

# **UX** Designer & Developer

# Contact

01630300341

Weimar, Germany

mohamad.g.khalil@gmail.com

mohamad-khalil.de

### Skills

#### **User-Research:**

Contextual Design
Ethnography
Speculative Prototyping

#### **UI Design:**

Figma, GIMP, Adobe Suite

#### **Web Development:**

HTML5, CSS, JavaScript

## **Programming:**

C++, Java

#### **Physical-Computing:**

Arduino, Node MCU esp8266

#### Languages

**Arabic** (native)

English (business fluent)

**German** (proficient)

**Turkish** (proficient)

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Architect**

May 2020 to Aug 2020

## **PAB Architects, Erfurt Germany**

Finalizing Architectural documents using Autodesk Revit and managing collaborative BIM work using Autodesk 360.

#### **Academic Assistant**

Apr 2019 to Jun 2019

#### **Bauhaus-Universität Weimar**

Architectural assistance in developing the site-specific Bauhaus100 project 'Bauhaus Orbits'

#### **Architect**

May 2014 to May 2017

#### Studio14

3D modeling and rendering architectural illustrations, designing architectural projects, drafting architectural and structural projects.

#### **Architect**

Oct 2013 to Apr 2014

#### **Ezcan Ozsoy**

3D modeling and rendering architectural illustrations, designing architectural projects, drafting architectural and structural projects.

## **EDUCATION**

# MediaArchitecture (M. Sc.)

Sep 2017 to Mar 2020

#### Bauhaus-Universität Weimar

In association with the Human-Computer Interaction department, I learned to develop physical and digital prototypes, and implement research methods in Human-Centered-Design.

My master thesis explored the intersection between meditation, intimacy, and distance communications. I finally developed the concept of 'Trans-local mindfulness', which was implemented by building two meditation devices and a custom mobile application.

## **Architecture (B. Arch.)**

Sep 2008 to Jul 2013

#### **Near East University**

With focus on 3D modeling, using building information modeling software, rendering, 2D drafting, and illustration.

# SKILLPROFIL

# Mohamad G. Khalil

# **UX** Designer & Developer

Figma

**Adobe Suite** 

**HTML** 

**CSS** 

**JavaScript** 

C++

Java

**Contextual Design** 

**Ethnography** 

**Prototyping** 

**Behavioral Psychology** 

**Public Speaking** 



# **User-Research & Testing**

**Software & Programming** 

